<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-02-15T10:40:10+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Running Challenges</title><subtitle>Collect badges and complete challenges for running, jogging, walking, and volunteering at your weekly 5k parkrun. This browser extension adds extra information to your parkrun results page so you can see your progress.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Freyne Club added and Tourism badge changes (v1.0.0)</title><link href="/2020/01/18/v1.0.0-freyne-club.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Freyne Club added and Tourism badge changes (v1.0.0)" /><published>2020-01-18T19:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-18T19:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2020/01/18/v1.0.0-freyne-club</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/01/18/v1.0.0-freyne-club.html">&lt;p&gt;Say hello to the new and improved Tourism and Obsessive Challenge tables, and the addition of the Freyne Club badge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tourism-challenge&quot;&gt;Tourism challenge?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tourist challenge and Cowell Club have now joined forces and are available under the single umbrella
of the “Tourism” challenge. You still get awarded the same badges as before, but now they appear as milestones
on your tourism journey, rather than as distinct challenge tables with their own separate lists of events.
This has several benefits that help people out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Tourism challenge never stops: you can see all the unique parkrun events you have run, 
and it doesn’t just stop when it reaches the number defined in the challenge (20,100, etc…).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We don’t have to repeat ourselves on the page: the Tourist Challenge (20 parkrun events) was a subset
of the Cowell Club Challenge (100 parkrun events), so we were wasting 20+ table rows by repeating those 
first 20 events.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s easy to add a new or different milestones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A picture describes it best, so here’s a screenshot from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.parkrun.org.uk/results/athleteeventresultshistory/?athleteNumber=1309364&amp;amp;eventNumber=0&quot;&gt;a parkrunner&lt;/a&gt; who has got their ‘Cow’ (Half Cowell), but hasn’t yet reached the lofty heights of the Cowell Club.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/tourism-challenge-table.png&quot; alt=&quot;Running Challenges Tourism Challenge Table&quot; title=&quot;Running challenges table for the Tourism Challenge with incomplete badges&quot; class=&quot;center-image image-border&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see in the picture, the point at which a badge is awarded is denoted by including a small version
of the badge at the start of that row.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;freyne-club-250-different-events&quot;&gt;Freyne club (250 different events)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The eagle-eyed among you may have noticed that there is another badge available beyond the Cowell Club at 100 events. 
This is for joining the Freyne club for which you need to have visited 250 different events! Like the Cowell Club, this 
was named by the parkrun tourist community by the first person to reach the milestone, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.parkrun.org.uk/results/athleteeventresultshistory/?athleteNumber=5227&amp;amp;eventNumber=0&quot;&gt;Paul FREYNE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a larger version of the new badge. We’ve taken to calling it the &lt;em&gt;Freyne Train&lt;/em&gt; :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/badges/runner-freyne-club.png&quot; alt=&quot;Running Challenges Freyne Club badge&quot; title=&quot;Running Challenges Freyne Club badge&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;only-250-different-events-hasnt-someone-already-got-to-500&quot;&gt;Only 250 different events? Hasn’t someone already got to 500?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of right now, the only person to achieve 500 different events appears to be … &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.parkrun.org.uk/results/athleteeventresultshistory/?athleteNumber=5227&amp;amp;eventNumber=0&quot;&gt;Paul FREYNE&lt;/a&gt;, he of the aforementioned 250 club fame.
This is a feat that only a handful of people are ever likely to achieve, and to make a badge for it now seems excessive.
If you’ve got the time, disposable income, and determination to get to that milestone, the personal satisfaction of 
reaching that mark will have to be enough for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;parkrun-obessive-improvements&quot;&gt;parkrun Obessive improvements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Obsessive badges were among the first challenges to be added to the extension, as counting up the number of
events run per year is pretty straightforward. :) There are, however, two things that were not quite right about 
this challenge:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We have always wanted to include volunteering in this count, not just running. We still can’t fix that yet because
parkrun still doesn’t display any information on the website to say when or where you have volunteered.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Why do you get all 3 badges (Bronze, Silver, and Gold) for doing 50+ in a single year as that isn’t how medals 
work… Well, this is something we can fix!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Obsessive challenge is now a single table and you can get at most one badge awarded per year. Additionally,
you can now also see the badges that you haven’t got yet (in a similar way to the tourism challenge) so that 
you can see what you are working towards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/obsessive-table.png&quot; alt=&quot;Running Challenges Obsessive Challenge Table&quot; title=&quot;Running challenges table for the Obsessive Challenge with incomplete badges&quot; class=&quot;center-image image-border&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-the-closest-parkrun-to-your-average-parkrun-location&quot;&gt;What’s the closest parkrun to your average parkrun location?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, we know that calculating your average parkrun location is a fairly useless stat but now we’ve extended it
to work out which parkrun event is the closest to that location. So you can go run it, if you want. Just click 
the parkrun’s name to find out more about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;version-100&quot;&gt;Version 1.0.0?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have been releasing this extension as version 0.something for nearly two years. We decided that it’s clearly 
working well enough to be worthly of a version 1 release! We’ll try and be a bit more logical with our numbering
system in the future, and increase the second number whenever we add a new badge, stat, or challenge, or something 
significant changes in the way things are displayed on the webpage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-do-i-get-all-of-this-great-stuff&quot;&gt;How do I get all of this great stuff?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have already installed the extension it should update soon. Typically we
have found it takes a few days for Chrome and Firefox to auto-update, but it should
do so eventually.  If you haven’t yet joined the fun you can get it from one of
the links below. :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/running-challenges/kdapmdimgdebpgolimjnmcdlkbkddoif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/ChromeWebStore_BadgeWBorder_v2_206x58.png&quot; alt=&quot;Running Challenges in the Chrome Web Store&quot; title=&quot;Running Challenges in the Chrome Web Store&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-GB/firefox/addon/running-challenges/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/firefox_web_store-172x60.png&quot; alt=&quot;Running Challenges in the Firefox Add-ons Web Store&quot; title=&quot;Running Challenges in the Firefox Add-ons Web Store&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Say hello to the new and improved Tourism and Obsessive Challenge tables, and the addition of the Freyne Club badge.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New parkrun Explorer map (v0.7.9)</title><link href="/2019/12/24/v0.7.9-released.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New parkrun Explorer map (v0.7.9)" /><published>2019-12-24T15:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-24T15:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2019/12/24/v0.7.9-released</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/12/24/v0.7.9-released.html">&lt;p&gt;Say hello to the new and improved parkrun explorer map!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-parkrun-explorer-map&quot;&gt;The parkrun explorer map?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes. You might remember this as being the map for the regionnaire challenge, but we’ve rebranded it and 
added some more goodies for those people who generally want to plan their touristing and want to 
visualise where they have run on a map. It now lives in-between the stats table and the challenge tables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-changed&quot;&gt;What’s changed?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have computed what is called a “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Voronoi_diagram&quot;&gt;voronoi diagram&lt;/a&gt;”. We 
have divided the world into cells. If you are within a particular cell, you know where the 
nearest parkrun is to that location. A picture is worth a thousand words, so here’s an example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/voronoi-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Running Challenges in the Chrome Web Store&quot; title=&quot;Running challenges voronoi diagram of the South coast of England&quot; class=&quot;center-image image-border&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A green cell shows that you have done the parkrun for that area. The circles representing the parkruns 
are green for ones you have done, and black for the others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zoom right in if you want to find out the name of the event you are looking at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/voronoi-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Running Challenges in the Chrome Web Store&quot; title=&quot;Zoomed in Running challenges voronoi diagram around Cheshire&quot; class=&quot;center-image image-border&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the old map we found that having over a thousand markers showing every parkrun didn’t scale - 
the map was overcrowded and slow to scroll and pan around. This new way seems to work much better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;do-we-have-regions-yet&quot;&gt;Do we have regions yet?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why not create your own region! Hopefully by colouring the cells in this way it should be easy to tell if you 
have been to all the events in a particular area of the country / world - just look for the contiguous green 
parts of the map!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;can-i-play-blockbusters-across-the-country-with-it&quot;&gt;Can I play Blockbusters across the country with it?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes. We think that would be an excellent idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll have a P please Bob - cue everyone heading off to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.parkrun.org.uk/penistone/&quot;&gt;Penistone parkrun&lt;/a&gt; :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;updated-japanese-and-polish-translations&quot;&gt;Updated Japanese and Polish translations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we added support for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.parkrun.jp/&quot;&gt;parkrun.jp&lt;/a&gt; no events had been run yet, and we didn’t know any
of the volunteer translations! Now, thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.parkrun.org.uk/results/athleteeventresultshistory/?athleteNumber=4782624&amp;amp;eventNumber=0&quot;&gt;William Steffancin (A4782624)&lt;/a&gt; we have example translations for most of the roles in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, in Poland, parkrun HQ updated most (all?) of the volunteer roles names, probably to be more technically
correct (the best kind of correct). Many thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sebiush&quot;&gt;@sebuish&lt;/a&gt; who has provided us with 
an updated list. The purple badges should be showing correctly for Poland once more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-do-i-get-all-of-this-great-stuff&quot;&gt;How do I get all of this great stuff?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have already installed the extension it should update soon - typically we
have found it takes a few days for Chrome and Firefox to auto-update, but it should
do so eventually.  If you haven’t yet joined the fun you can get it from one of
the links below. :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/running-challenges/kdapmdimgdebpgolimjnmcdlkbkddoif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/ChromeWebStore_BadgeWBorder_v2_206x58.png&quot; alt=&quot;Running Challenges in the Chrome Web Store&quot; title=&quot;Running Challenges in the Chrome Web Store&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-GB/firefox/addon/running-challenges/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/firefox_web_store-172x60.png&quot; alt=&quot;Running Challenges in the Firefox Add-ons Web Store&quot; title=&quot;Running Challenges in the Firefox Add-ons Web Store&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Say hello to the new and improved parkrun explorer map!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Special events map for 2019/2020</title><link href="/2019/12/19/special-events-map-for-2019-2020.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Special events map for 2019/2020" /><published>2019-12-19T22:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-19T22:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2019/12/19/special-events-map-for-2019-2020</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/12/19/special-events-map-for-2019-2020.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s that time of the year for the extra festive parkrun events!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were a bit late to the game and have missed the Thanksgiving extras,
but there is still change to find your local event that is doing the 
Christmas Day/Eve/Boxing Day or New Year’s Day parkruns!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;/map&quot;&gt;the map here&lt;/a&gt;, and there is another link at the top
of this page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with last year, you can filter on the time as well as the day, so you can find
the closest event to you that gets you the amount of sleep you like :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We think we’ve got all the countries, and have listed them under their English 
translations, so you’l find Christmas Eve in Denmark and Boxing Day in Germany.
Hopefully we’ve got them translated right!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in a New Year’s Day Double, don’t forget &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rikkiprince&quot;&gt;Rikki Prince’s&lt;/a&gt;
amazing &lt;a href=&quot;https://tailrun.uk/nyd/2020/&quot;&gt;Double Finder Tool&lt;/a&gt; to see which ones you
might be able to do!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/running-challenges/kdapmdimgdebpgolimjnmcdlkbkddoif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/ChromeWebStore_BadgeWBorder_v2_206x58.png&quot; alt=&quot;Running Challenges in the Chrome Web Store&quot; title=&quot;Running Challenges in the Chrome Web Store&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-GB/firefox/addon/running-challenges/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/firefox_web_store-172x60.png&quot; alt=&quot;Running Challenges in the Firefox Add-ons Web Store&quot; title=&quot;Running Challenges in the Firefox Add-ons Web Store&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It’s that time of the year for the extra festive parkrun events!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Where did my flags go?</title><link href="/2019/11/19/where-did-my-flags-go.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Where did my flags go?" /><published>2019-11-19T20:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-19T20:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2019/11/19/where-did-my-flags-go</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/11/19/where-did-my-flags-go.html">&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed that your flags have disappeared, you can’t save your athlete ID in
the options page, your regionnaire badge has disappeared, or you no longer have your NENDY 
and average parkrun location listed… Read on to find out what broke, why, and what we’re doing 
to fix it…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-broke&quot;&gt;What broke?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Running Challenges extension uses the location of parkruns to determine which countries you 
have been to - adding flags under your badges, to generate the Regionnaire challenge info, as 
well as work out stats such as your NENDY.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were also some knock on errors, which wouldn’t have happened if we had coded the extension
to cope with the event location data being missing, such as saving your profile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-did-it-break&quot;&gt;Why did it break?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the summer the main parkrun website changed the way they generated the event map - 
out went a XML file (geo.xml) that had existed from the Google Maps days, and in came a 
JSON file (events.json). The new file was much more efficient to render the event markers 
on the map, but broke our extension…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;has-it-been-fixed&quot;&gt;Has it been fixed?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes and no. Most of the extension is back to full strength - the flags are still available, 
and you’ll still be able to determine your NENDY, but the Regionnaire challenge is missing
parts. We’ve also made the code more robust if data is missing. It won’t be bulletproof, but 
hopefully it is better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-state-of-the-regionnaire-challenge&quot;&gt;The state of the Regionnaire challenge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only regions that we now have access to in the events data are the countries, there are no
subregions in the data we pull down. Not every country had sub-regions before, so for parkrunners in 
the USA, or most of Europe, there is no change. The UK, Australia, and South Africa were the 
largest ones with sub-regions, and now all those parkruns are counted against the country at a single 
level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As there isn’t any sensible sub-division, the regionnaire challenge badge would effectively only be 
achieveable for those people who had done every event in a whole country - so it has been removed for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Regionnaire table remains, but now it is more of a parkrun event explorer - showing you how many 
events you have done in each country, and allowing you to browse them on the map. As yet there is no
highlighting of which ones have been done, but that’ll probably be re-introduced as time allows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-but-i-want-my-regions-back&quot;&gt;But, but, I want my regions back!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there is a simple and sensible way of making them return, we will try to do so. We don’t want to spend hours
crafting a list, and we certainly don’t want to be drawn into debates about which region an event should 
go in. We’ll see how it goes without the information for now, fix a few other things first, and then 
come back to looking at it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/running-challenges/kdapmdimgdebpgolimjnmcdlkbkddoif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/ChromeWebStore_BadgeWBorder_v2_206x58.png&quot; alt=&quot;Running Challenges in the Chrome Web Store&quot; title=&quot;Running Challenges in the Chrome Web Store&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-GB/firefox/addon/running-challenges/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/firefox_web_store-172x60.png&quot; alt=&quot;Running Challenges in the Firefox Add-ons Web Store&quot; title=&quot;Running Challenges in the Firefox Add-ons Web Store&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">You may have noticed that your flags have disappeared, you can’t save your athlete ID in the options page, your regionnaire badge has disappeared, or you no longer have your NENDY and average parkrun location listed… Read on to find out what broke, why, and what we’re doing to fix it…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Version 0.7.6 Released</title><link href="/2019/06/09/v0.7.6-released.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Version 0.7.6 Released" /><published>2019-06-09T22:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-06-09T22:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/2019/06/09/v0.7.6-released</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/06/09/v0.7.6-released.html">&lt;p&gt;Full Ponty challenge extended and the addition of a new stat - the v-index!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;full-ponty-challenge&quot;&gt;Full Ponty challenge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in April a new parkrun started in Bala, Wales, and it was officially named
as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.parkrun.org.uk/pontybala/&quot;&gt;Pont y Bala&lt;/a&gt;. This update includes the
Bala parkrun in the Full Ponty challenge that so many people love :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;v-index-stat&quot;&gt;v-index stat&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The p-index generated a lot of interest - and quite a bit of confusion, when it
was first introduced, so the v-index doubles the fun :) Instead of having to do
some parkrun tourism to improve your p-index, the v-index focuses on different
volunteering roles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was first mentioned by Mel in &lt;a href=&quot;https://parkrunadventurers.podbean.com/e/episode-158-v-index/&quot;&gt;Episode 158&lt;/a&gt;
of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/parkrunadventurers/&quot;&gt;parkrun adventurers&lt;/a&gt; podcast -
check it out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s all very simple, it is the number of different volunteering roles, v, that
you have done at least v times each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/johnsyweb&quot;&gt;Pete Johns&lt;/a&gt; from Melbourne who
wrote the initial code to add this based on the p-index, and created a pull-request
in GitHub so we could included it - Nice one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-do-i-get-all-of-this-great-stuff&quot;&gt;How do I get all of this great stuff?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have already installed the extension it should update soon - typically we
have found it takes a few days for Chrome and Firefox to auto-update, but it should
do so eventually.  If you haven’t yet joined the fun you can get it from one of
the links below. :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/running-challenges/kdapmdimgdebpgolimjnmcdlkbkddoif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/ChromeWebStore_BadgeWBorder_v2_206x58.png&quot; alt=&quot;Running Challenges in the Chrome Web Store&quot; title=&quot;Running Challenges in the Chrome Web Store&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-GB/firefox/addon/running-challenges/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/firefox_web_store-172x60.png&quot; alt=&quot;Running Challenges in the Firefox Add-ons Web Store&quot; title=&quot;Running Challenges in the Firefox Add-ons Web Store&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Full Ponty challenge extended and the addition of a new stat - the v-index!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Alphabeteer Panic - What Happened to Zary?</title><link href="/2019/05/19/alphabeteer-panic-what-happened-to-zary.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Alphabeteer Panic - What Happened to Zary?" /><published>2019-05-19T12:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-19T12:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/2019/05/19/alphabeteer-panic-what-happened-to-zary</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/05/19/alphabeteer-panic-what-happened-to-zary.html">&lt;p&gt;It is
becoming quite a challenge in itself to reply to every comment or email about
why Żary parkrun no longer counts towards the Alphabeteer A-Z challenge. It has come up so many times now that it is worthy of a blog post -
hopefully this can set the record straight, with all the facts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-happened&quot;&gt;What Happened?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the start of May 2019, parkrun HQ &lt;del&gt;changed&lt;/del&gt; corrected the spelling of Żary
parkrun in the results table, it now accurately starts with a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Ż&lt;/code&gt;, and not a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Z&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Polish alphabet contains many letters that are not in the UK English alphabet,
with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Ż&lt;/code&gt; being one of them. Of the 66 current parkruns shown on the map in Poland, the following
list shows those that have an initial letter not in the UK English alphabet:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.parkrun.pl/lodz/&quot;&gt;Łódź&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.parkrun.pl/swidwin/&quot;&gt;Świdwin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.parkrun.pl/swinoujscie/&quot;&gt;Świnoujście&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.parkrun.pl/zary/&quot;&gt;Żary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The extension currently checks whether the first letter of a parkrun name is one of the characters in the
list &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;abcdefghijklmnopqrstuvwyz&lt;/code&gt; i.e. one of the characters of the UK Engish
alphabet, minus the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;X&lt;/code&gt;. A computer programme does not know if the letters look
the same, it has a unique code for each letter - therefore &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Ż&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Z&lt;/code&gt; are never
matched together. With that in mind, &lt;strong&gt;we did not remove Żary from counting as a Z&lt;/strong&gt;,
it merely no longer starts with a character that we check for, and thus it effectively
became invisible in the Alphabeteer challenge in the Running Challenges extension. &lt;strong&gt;There has been no change in the
Running Challenges Extension code&lt;/strong&gt;, this change in behaviour is purely down to
the change in the way the event name is displayed in the results table - a change
made by parkrun HQ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be clear, the Running Challenges Extension is not affiliated with parkrun, and
as it says in our &lt;a href=&quot;/about&quot;&gt;About page&lt;/a&gt;, it is made by a couple of keen parkrunners who just
wanted to share a cool tool they made. We don’t get notified in advance of any parkrun website changes; if it breaks something in the Running Challenges extension, we just have to catch up and fix it. The first we heard of the
change in the way Żary is written was when we were on holiday in Cornwall!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-did-it-change&quot;&gt;Why Did It Change?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we are unaffiliated with parkrun HQ, we have no insight into why this was
changed now, but we can (and will!) speculate. The primary reason is that it was
wrong! &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Ż&lt;/code&gt; is not the same as &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Z&lt;/code&gt;, and being correct is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As parkrun becomes ever more global it has to make sure the
events in each country are accessible to those local communities. Having your
local parkrun incorrectly spelt on the website can only hinder native Polish parkrunners
finding it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edit: 20190522. Word on the street is that the Polish parkrun community wanted
the parkrun spelt correctly on their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.prodirectrunning.com/articles/parkrun/parkrun-apricot/&quot;&gt;apricot tees&lt;/a&gt;, seems reasonable!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;From our secret source: &amp;quot;The reason the Z was changed in Poland was because of the new Apricot t-shirts. The Poles wanted the correct alphabet for all the events. It didn’t come from HQ, but of course we did it for them.&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And rightly so too. 👏👏👏 &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/YRplDIeOOd&quot;&gt;https://t.co/YRplDIeOOd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; With Me Now (@WithMeNowPod) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/WithMeNowPod/status/1131128642652856320?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;May 22, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-does-it-matter-to-alphabeteers&quot;&gt;Why Does It Matter To Alphabeteers?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is well known in the parkrun tourist communities that some initial letters
are harder to get than others. For a long time,  Jersey parkrun
was the only event on the UK parkrun website that began with a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;J&lt;/code&gt;, and there were many grumblings about ‘having’
to go to beautiful Channel Islands to get that letter. The more extreme case is
for a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Z&lt;/code&gt;, where the nearest one was in &lt;del&gt;Zary&lt;/del&gt; Żary, Poland. To some, finding
that &lt;del&gt;Zary&lt;/del&gt; Żary is not being counted as a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Z&lt;/code&gt; is &lt;strong&gt;the-worst-thing-in-the-world™&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-else-might-change&quot;&gt;What Else Might Change?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The eagle-eyed amongst you will have noticed that all the Russian parkrun events
are listed in the results table in their English spellings, take
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.parkrun.ru/gorkypark/&quot;&gt;Gorky Park&lt;/a&gt; for example, which is actually
called “parkrun Парк Горького”, or maybe &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.parkrun.jp/futakotamagawa/&quot;&gt;二子玉川 parkrun&lt;/a&gt;, which   begins
with “二”, “ふ”, or (at a push) an “F”. It is probably only a matter of time before these
corrections are also made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-is-the-running-challenge-extension-going-to-cope&quot;&gt;How is the Running Challenge Extension Going to Cope?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good question. Whatever we decide will unfortunately be seen to favour one group
over another. However, where possible we have always tried to include the worldwide
parkrun family and not make this extension exclusively UK only, so our solution
will attempt to respect that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing we will definitely &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; be doing is counting Żary as a Z, that
makes no sense - the letters are as similar as O and Q, but no-one is suggesting
that those two are interchangeable!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is likely that we will split the Alphabeteer challenges up into country variants,
and include a master list for those people wanting to truly get the whole list.
This will have the following advantages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Those parkrunners who don’t want to, or can’t, go abroad will be able to track
their local progress against the available alphabet letters in their country.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The master list will allow anyone to track any specific subset they are interested
in, and if they want to track Żary as a Z, they can see that it has been done.
But this won’t mean the badge is available for arbitrary subsets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-isnt-it-fixed-yet&quot;&gt;Why Isn’t it Fixed Yet?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are not enough hours in the day! We have full-time jobs, other hobbies, and lives outside of parkrun, we’ll do the changes when we can. As you
can hopefully see from the above explanation, however, it’s not a trivial change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t yet joined the fun, you can get the extension from one of
the links below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/running-challenges/kdapmdimgdebpgolimjnmcdlkbkddoif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/ChromeWebStore_BadgeWBorder_v2_206x58.png&quot; alt=&quot;Running Challenges in the Chrome Web Store&quot; title=&quot;Running Challenges in the Chrome Web Store&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-GB/firefox/addon/running-challenges/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/firefox_web_store-172x60.png&quot; alt=&quot;Running Challenges in the Firefox Add-ons Web Store&quot; title=&quot;Running Challenges in the Firefox Add-ons Web Store&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It is becoming quite a challenge in itself to reply to every comment or email about why Żary parkrun no longer counts towards the Alphabeteer A-Z challenge. It has come up so many times now that it is worthy of a blog post - hopefully this can set the record straight, with all the facts.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Version 0.7.5 Released</title><link href="/2019/04/04/v0.7.5-released.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Version 0.7.5 Released" /><published>2019-04-04T20:24:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-04-04T20:24:00+01:00</updated><id>/2019/04/04/v0.7.5-released</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/04/04/v0.7.5-released.html">&lt;p&gt;parkrun Japan is coming!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week parkrun starts in &lt;a href=&quot;https://parkrun.jp&quot;&gt;Japan&lt;/a&gt;, and to make sure we are ready for it we have proactively put out this release to include the necessary changes to support the new site at &lt;a href=&quot;https://parkrun.jp&quot;&gt;parkrun.jp&lt;/a&gt;. Obviously the website is all in Japanese, and hopefully we’ve done everything right to ensure the badges, challenges and stats appear in the correct places on the new website. There should also be a Japanese flag available for anyone completing a run in Japan!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this update includes overlaying data on a new domain (i.e. parkrun.jp), when the extension updates it will require extra permissions to do so - the extension will likely be disabled until you do this. If you are using Chrome the icon may be a yellow circle instead of the usual green running man icon, and clicking on the yellow icon will allow you to accept the new permissions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, we have added the new volunteer badge recently introduced by parkrun HQ for the &lt;strong&gt;Event Day Course Check&lt;/strong&gt; role. You can see the new badge over at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://running-challenges.co.uk/badges/&quot;&gt;badges page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy parkrunning!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have already installed the extension it should update soon - typically we
have found it takes a few days for Chrome and Firefox to auto-update, but it should
do so eventually. As mentioned above, you will likely need to accept the new permission before it will load. If you haven’t yet joined the fun you can get it from one of
the links below. :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/running-challenges/kdapmdimgdebpgolimjnmcdlkbkddoif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/ChromeWebStore_BadgeWBorder_v2_206x58.png&quot; alt=&quot;Running Challenges in the Chrome Web Store&quot; title=&quot;Running Challenges in the Chrome Web Store&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-GB/firefox/addon/running-challenges/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/firefox_web_store-172x60.png&quot; alt=&quot;Running Challenges in the Firefox Add-ons Web Store&quot; title=&quot;Running Challenges in the Firefox Add-ons Web Store&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">parkrun Japan is coming!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Special-Events Website Map</title><link href="/2018/12/16/new-website-map.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Special-Events Website Map" /><published>2018-12-16T23:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-16T23:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2018/12/16/new-website-map</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/12/16/new-website-map.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s time for the festive extra events!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Christmas / New Year period brings the possibility of extra parkruns to
volunteer and run at, and however you choose to spend your time you might be
wondering what events are on, and at what time - especially if you intend to
dash between a couple of them on New Year’s Day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that all the parkrun teams have announced which events are taking place,
we’ve hastily cobbled together a map on the website that displays them all for
you on one map - and you can switch between which special event, and which times,
to look for the ones you are interested in. It’s very rough, but this information
is going to be useless in a week or two, so we are just putting out what we’ve
done so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;/map&quot;&gt;the map here&lt;/a&gt;, and there is another link at the top
of this page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope it’s useful to someone!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please note: We are missing a few countries where the events aren’t listed in
English, we’ll try and add those in as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/running-challenges/kdapmdimgdebpgolimjnmcdlkbkddoif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/ChromeWebStore_BadgeWBorder_v2_206x58.png&quot; alt=&quot;Running Challenges in the Chrome Web Store&quot; title=&quot;Running Challenges in the Chrome Web Store&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-GB/firefox/addon/running-challenges/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/firefox_web_store-172x60.png&quot; alt=&quot;Running Challenges in the Firefox Add-ons Web Store&quot; title=&quot;Running Challenges in the Firefox Add-ons Web Store&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It’s time for the festive extra events!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Version 0.7.4 Released</title><link href="/2018/12/03/v0.7.4-released.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Version 0.7.4 Released" /><published>2018-12-03T23:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-03T23:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2018/12/03/v0.7.4-released</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/12/03/v0.7.4-released.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s Christmas!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, it’s Christmas soon, and to celebrate, we have released a new running
badge to adorn those runners who have managed to run on Christmas day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(We’d really like to give extra special kudos to those volunteers giving up their
Christmas morning, but until the parkrun website lists the dates of each volunteer
role, unfortunately we aren’t able to do so.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, we have added the ‘All Weather Runner’ badge, contributed by
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rboyatt&quot;&gt;Russell Boyatt&lt;/a&gt; - this badge celebrates those parkrunners
who have kept up their attendence come rain or shime and have run at least once
in every calendar month (they don’t have to be in the same year).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/badges/runner-christmas-day.png&quot; alt=&quot;Run on Christmas Day (25th December)&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/badges/runner-all-weather-runner.png&quot; alt=&quot;All Weather Runner - Run in each month of the year (not necessarily in the same year)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy parkrunning!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have already installed the extension it should update soon - typically we
have found it takes a few days for Chrome and Firefox to auto-update, but it should
do so eventually. If you haven’t yet joined the fun you can get it from one of
the links below. :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/running-challenges/kdapmdimgdebpgolimjnmcdlkbkddoif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/ChromeWebStore_BadgeWBorder_v2_206x58.png&quot; alt=&quot;Running Challenges in the Chrome Web Store&quot; title=&quot;Running Challenges in the Chrome Web Store&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-GB/firefox/addon/running-challenges/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/firefox_web_store-172x60.png&quot; alt=&quot;Running Challenges in the Firefox Add-ons Web Store&quot; title=&quot;Running Challenges in the Firefox Add-ons Web Store&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It’s Christmas!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Version 0.7.3 Released</title><link href="/2018/10/27/v0.7.3-released.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Version 0.7.3 Released" /><published>2018-10-27T20:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-10-27T20:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/2018/10/27/v0.7.3-released</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/10/27/v0.7.3-released.html">&lt;p&gt;Now with the Car Park Marshal badge!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the latest of a number of small updates, including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Addition of the “Tourism Streak” stat&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Addition of a map link to the average parkrun location stat&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reorganisation of the Regionnaire section to make it more compact&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Updating (possibly completing!) the volunteer role translations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Addition of the Car Park Marshal volunteer role badge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have already installed the extension it should update soon, if not you can get it
from one of the links below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/running-challenges/kdapmdimgdebpgolimjnmcdlkbkddoif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/ChromeWebStore_BadgeWBorder_v2_206x58.png&quot; alt=&quot;Running Challenges in the Chrome Web Store&quot; title=&quot;Running Challenges in the Chrome Web Store&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-GB/firefox/addon/running-challenges/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/firefox_web_store-172x60.png&quot; alt=&quot;Running Challenges in the Firefox Add-ons Web Store&quot; title=&quot;Running Challenges in the Firefox Add-ons Web Store&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Now with the Car Park Marshal badge!</summary></entry></feed>